Reem Alattas

617.331.9040

ralattas@live.com www.ReemAlattas.com

Profile

Multi-lingual self-motivated contributor imbibing knowledge through execution excellence. Five years of diverse experiences, including software engineering, teaching, researching, service delivery management, sales excellence management, acting and fitness training. Energy and enthusiasm enables to do the work efficiently and achieving the goals of the organization.

Experience

Web Developer, Startup Institute; New York, New York - Oct 2015-Present

Focus on Ruby on Rails, test-driven development, git, AWS, Heroku, node.js and mobile-first methodology. Work on projects for Vesper and OS Fashion Startups.

Licensing Sales Specialist, Microsoft; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia — Jan 2011-Jun 2011 Sales leadership combining Licensing, Sales Excellence, and Business Planning Management for Small and Mid- Market Solutions and Partners (SMS&P).

Technical Account Manager, Microsoft; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia — May 2009-Dec2010

Manage a moderate to complex scope of support issues of Premier customers by acting as a technical resource and coordinating with other Microsoft groups to assist the customer in their use, support and implementation of Microsoft solutions.

Lecturer, Institute of Public Administration; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia — Apr 2007-Apr 2009 Adjunct Lecturer, Arab Open University; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia — Sep 2005-Apr 2009

Teach computer science classes to different students daily, ranging from diploma to bachelor students and government employees.

Software Engineer, Banque Saudi Fransi; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia — May 2004-Aug 2005 Design and implement online banking system and IPO system using .NET technologies.

Education

University of Bridgeport; Bridgeport, CT – PhD in Computer Science & Engineering, 2017 (Expected)

MIT; Online - Tackling the Challenges of Big Data, 2014

Tufts University; Medford, MA – Human Computer Interaction, 2013

Harvard University; Cambridge, MA - Becoming an Agent of Change, 2012

Simmons College; Boston, MA - Communication Strategies, 2011

King Saud University; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia – MSc in Computer Science, 2007 King Saud University; Riyadh, Saudi Arabia – BSc in Computer Science, 2007

Certifications

PMP - Project Management Professional Certificate, 2010

ITIL - Information Technology Infrastructure Library V3 Foundation Certificate, 2009

MOF - Microsoft Operations Framework Foundation Certificate, 2009